Finding Aid for the Harold Stirling Vanderbilt Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- McGaw, Robert A., June 26, 1962
- Rogers, David E., May 8, 1962
- Stambaugh, John H., May 30, 1962
- Stevenson, Eldon., Apr. 2, 1962; May 28, 1962; June 20, 1962
- Stocking, George., July 28, 1961
- Trabue, Charles C., May 10, 1962; June 22, 1962
- Wade, John W., July 26, 1961
- Vanderbilt University Correspondence — Chancellorship, Outgoing
- 1961: July 21, Faculty Committee; July 24, Board of Trust Committee; July 3, Board Committee; Aug. 4, Willard B. Jewell; Aug. 11, Amos Christie; J. Philip Hyatt; George W. Stocking; John W. Wade Sept. 18, W.B. Jewell; Dec. 20, Jewell
- 1962: Jan. 9, Henry Alexander; W.B. Jewell; Feb. 21, Sam Fleming; Mar 2, Leonard Beach; Mar 26, Henry C. Alexander; Mar 30, Alexander; Sam Fleming; Apr 4, Fleming; Apr 6, Alexander; Apr 14, Alexander; Apr 19, Branscomb; Apr 27, Heard; Apr 30, Alexander May 7, Heard; May 7, Alexander; Robert L. Garner; Eldon Stevenson,Jr. May 10, Heard; May 14, Joe Schimmel; David E. Rogers; May 25, Eldon Stevenson-, May 25, Heard; May 28, Heard; May 31, Heard; June 1, Stambaugh; June 2, Committee; June 4., Branscomb; June 12, Branscomb; June 18, Alumni Association, June 19, Houston; Jesse E. Johnson; June 19, J.L. Boren; Alumni Assoc; Alexander; June 21, Walter N. Thayer; June 22, Robert McGaw; Eldon Stevenson, June 25, Leonard B. Beach; Don Elliott; June 28, Eldon Stevenson; July 2, Branscomb; Heard; July 18, Heard; Alexander
- Vanderbilt University Correspondence — the James H. Kirkland - William K. Vanderbilt Correspondence
- W.K. Vanderbilt — Incoming
- Jan. 29, 1904; Feb. 10, 1904; June 4, 1908; June 10, 1908; July 12, 1909; Aug. 25, 1909 May 19, 1910; with reciepts for gifts to Vanderbilt University Sept. 26, 1920; Oct. 26, 1920; Oct. 27; Nov. 15, Dec. 23, Dec. 28, 1910 Jan. 4; Jan. 7; Jan. 12; Jan. 16, 1911 Oct. 9, 1915, Oct. 16, 1915; Oct. 21, 1916; Oct. 31, 1916; March 5, 1917, March 14, 1917; Dec. 28, 1917; Jan. 14, 1918; Jan. 22, 1918; Jeb. 27, 1920; March 3, 1920; Sept. 22, 1919; Oct. 27, 1919; Nov. 24, 1919; Dec. 26, 1919; Jan. 3, 1920; Mar. 2, 1920; Mar. 6, 1920
- W.K.Vanderbilt — Outgoing
- Feb. 3, 1904; May 24, 1910; May 24, 1910; Sept. 28, 1910; Dec. 28, 1910; Jan. 3, 1911 Jan. 9, 1911; Oct. 13, 1915; Nov. 3, 1916; March 12, 1917; Jan. 17, 1918; Oct. 31, 1919; Nov. 20, 1919; Dec. 30, 1919; Dec. 31, 1919; Dec. 22, 1919; Feb. 28. 1920: Mar 2. 1920: n.d.
- Bridge Correspondence - Incoming
- 3-1 Baldwin, Russell J. Feb. 15, 1963 Becker, B. Jay. Sept. 25, 1964 Buhler, H.L. March 21, 1941 Butler, Geoffrey, L. June 9, 1960
- Ensko, Stephen., Apr. 30, 1959; May 15, 1959; Oct. 15, 1959; Mar 18, 1964 Fleming, Sam. Oct 5, 1964
- Frey, Richard L., Feb. 4, July 16; July 18; Oct. 25, 1963; Feb. 14; Mar 23; Apr 27, 1964; Jacoby, Oswald. Oct. 5, 1964; Dec. 24, 1964; July 28; Oct. 7, 1964
- Landy, Alvin., May 8, 1959; April 9, 1962; Mar 30, 1965; Lanier, Claudia W. Oct. 3, 1964; July 28, n.d. Little, S. George. Dec. 20, 1961 Lynn, George E. Sept. 18, 1964
- McGrover, Raymond J., May 29, 1961; June 28, 1961
- Miller, R.A., Nov. 1, 1964
- Morehead, Albert.
- Oct. 1, 1958; Feb. 24; Mar 10; July 16, 1959; July 20, Aug. 9; Aug. 22; Nov. 10; Nov. 18; Nov. 29, 1960; Aug. 17; Sept. 19, 1961; Aug. 4,; Aug. 25; Nov. 16; Jan. 7, 1962; Jan. 24, Feb. 8; Feb. 20; Feb. 27; Mar 9; Mar 12; Mar 28, 1963; Mar 28; May 20; May 23; July 10, 1963; Jan. 7; July 1, July 2, July 13, Sept. 16, 1964
- 3-2 Moyse, Alphonse. Mar 23, 1964; April 2, 1964; June 11, 1964 Murray, E.R., Mar 28, 1961
- Nexon, Baron R. de. Sept. 22, 1958 Nexus, Robert. May 4, 1960 Noble, Theodore E., Sept. 11, 1964; Oct. 5, 1964
- Osborn, Florence., Oct. 10, 1964
- Rasmussen, Barbara., Jan. 24, 1964; May 27, 1964 Robinson, Louis C. Aug. 2, 1961
- Schenken, Howard., [Oct. 1961]; Jan. 6; Mar 24; July 6; Thanksgiving Day; Dec. 17, n.d. Scribner, Charles, Jr. June 24; Aug. 19; Sept. 18; Oct. 7; Oct. 22; Oct 30; Nov. 1; Nov. 15; Dec. 4; Dec. 6; Dec. 9; Dec. 16, 1963; Jan. 3; Jan. 13; Mar. 12; Mar. 19; Mar. 31; May 5; May 15; June 22, 1964
- 3-3 Sheinwold, Alfred, July 6, 1961 Solomon, Charles J. May 23, 1961 Stern, Roger D. Oct. 16, 1961 Stoddard, Tom. Oct. 3, 1967 Taylor, Helen. Oct. 8, 1964 Taylor, J. Eugene. Jan. 29, 1963 Truscott, Alan. Feb. 5, 1963; Sept. 24, 1964 Waller, William. Oct. 5, 1964
- 3-4 Zedtwitz, Waldemar von., Dec 10, 1960; Apr. 12, 1961; June 22, 1961; July 12; July 28; Aug. 18; Aug. 24; Sept. 11; Sept. 14, with a draft of the laws, 1962; Sept. 22; Sept. 25, 1961; Aug. 23; Oct. 3; Oct. 5; Nov. 16, 1962; Mar 7; Mar 11; Apr 7; June 19; Sept 26, 1963; Sept 9, 1964; Jan 31; Oct 9 Oct. 2, 1964
- 3-5 Bridge Correspondence - Outgoing
- Capt. A.M. Gruenther, 1940: Feb. 5
- Waldy Zedtwitz, 1958: Nov. 19
- Albert Morehead; May 11, Stephen Ensko; June 12, Stephen Ensko; Nov. 5, Ensko, 1959: Mar 1
- Beoffrey L. Butler; Aug. 2, Morehead; Zedtwitz; Sept. 6, Morehead; Nov. 23, Hedtwitz; Nov. 23, Morehead, 1960: June 24
- American Contract Bridge League; May 12, Zedtwitz, etc.; May 19, Zedtwitz, etc. May 25, Zedtwitz, etc., 1961: Jan. 23
- 3-6 1961: June 19, Drafting Committee; June 28, Zedtwitz; July 12, Sheinwold; Aug. 17, Zedwitz; Aug. 17, George S. Coffin; Sept. 6, Morehead; Sept 6, Drafting Com. Oct. 18, Alvin Landy; Dec. 7, John R. Crawford; Dec. 8, Norman P. Ross; Dec. 8, Charles H. Goren; Dec. 12; H. Schenken; Dec. 27, Schenken
- 962: Jan. 2, S. George Little; Alfred Sheinwold; Feb. 22, Howard Schenken; Feb. 26, Schenken; Apr 5, Zedtwitz; Apr 13; Landy; July 6, Morehead; July 10, Schenken; Aug. 20, Morehead; Aug. 24, Zedtwitz; Aug. 27, Morehead; Oct. 5, Zedtwitz; Nov. 13, Morehead
- 3-7 1963: Jan. 3, Morehead; Jan 15, Morehead; Feb. 4, Eugene Taylor; Feb. 12, Morehead; Feb. 21, Alan Truscott; Feb. 21, Morehead; Richard L. Frey; Feb. 22, Truscott; Morehead; Feb. 26, Truscott, Mar 1, Morehead; Mar 15, Morehead; Zedtwitz; Apr. 2, Morehead; May 21, Sheinwold; May 27, Sheinwold; June 20, Scribner July 9, Morehead, July 12, Landy; Zedtwitz; July 17, Frey; July 24, Frey; Aug. 16, Scribners; Sept. 19, Scribner; Sept. 23, Zedtwitz; Oct 1, Zedtwitz; Oct. 17, Zedtwitz; Oct. 18, Scribners; Oct. 29, Scribners; Oct. 31, Scribner; Nov. 14, Scribner; Nov. 18, Scribner; Nov. 21, Nov. 26, Dec. 2, Dec. 4, Dec. 6, Charles Scribner
- 3-8 1964: Jan 7, Scribner, Jan 17, Scribner; Jan. 29, Rasmussen, Feb. 19, Frey; Mar 16, Scribner; Mar 26, Alphonse Moyse; Mar 27, Frey; Scribner; Mar 31, Truscott, Apr 10, Moyse; Apr 24, Moyse; Apr 28, Moyse; Scribner; Apr 30, Scribner; May 4, Frey; May 13, Scribner; May 28, Rasmussen; June 16, Scribner; June 17, Scribner; June 19, Moyse; June 26, Morehead; July 9, Morehead; July 14, Truscott; July 16, Morehead; Aug. 3, Sartain Lanier; Sept. 4, Moyse; Sept. 14, Zedtwitz; Sept. 15, Moble; Sept. 16, Edward White; Sept 21, George E. Lynn; Sept. 25, Truscott; Oct. 9, Florence Osborn; Oct. 30, Oswald Jacoby; Dec. 15, Jacoby
- Jacoby, 1965: July 29
- American Contract Bridge League, 1967: July 24
- Yachting Correspondence -- Incoming
- 6-1 Bavier, Robert N., Jr. (North American Yacht Racing Union) Nov. 23, 1959, with letter to Mr. J. Amory Jeffries; Nov 12, 1959; Dec. 3, 1959; Dec. 29, 1959 with Report from the Racing Rules Committee; Jan. 22, 1960; Oct. 5, 1960 (Yachting) with Czechoslovakia's Rules Submission; Nov. 7, 1960, Oct. 9, 1963
- 6-2 Bemis, F. Gregg. Nov. 30, 1959, with memorandum on classifying the Racing Rules, Sailing Rules when Yachts meet, on numbering the Rules; Jan. 6, 1960; Jan. 25; Jan. 27; Feb. 11, with minutes of Feb. 9 meeting, Feb. 20; Feb. 23; Mar 23; Mar 24; Mar 31; Apr 13; Apr 20; Apr 21; Apr 25; Apr 25; May 9; May 16; May 19; May 27; May 27; June 3; June 8; June 13; June 16; June 20; June 27; June 30, 1960.
- 6-3 July 1, 1960; July 4; July 6; July 12; July 29; Aug 2; Aug 5; Aug 8; Aug 18; Sept 15; Sept 22; Sept 27; Oct 5; Oct 10, 1960; Jan 3, 1961; Apr 18;May 2; May 25; May 26; June 15; June 28, 1961
- 6-4 July 3, 1961; July 10; July 14; July 21; July 27; Aug 4; Aug 7; Aug 14; Aug 18; Aug 28; Sept. 11; Sept 20; Sept 22; Oct 5; Oct 9; Oct 17; Oct 19; Oct 26; Nov. 20; Nov. 24; Nov. 30, 1961
- 6-5 Dec. 7 1961; Dec. 27, 1961; Jan. 8, 1962; Jan 9; Jan 15; Jan 16; Feb 1; Mar 2; Mar 20; Apr 27; May 11; May 15; May 24; July 17; July 20; July 31; Sept 14; Nov 9; Nov 16; Nov 30; Dec 7; Dec. 17; Dec. 18; Dec. 19, 1962
- 6-6 Jan 28, 1963; Jan 29; Feb. 14; Feb 25; Mar 5; Mar 24; Apr 22; Apr 23; Apr 30; May 6; May 7; May 10; May 13; May 16; May 20; May 22; Jun 10; Jun 10; July 2; July 22; Aug 22; Aug 27; Sept 10; Sept 30; Oct 7; Oct. 14; Oct 21; Nov 18, 1963
- 6-7 Mar 16, 1964; Apr 10; Apr 17; Apr 30; May 1; May 4; May 20; May 25; May 26; June 22; June 23; July 20; Aug 3; Aug 24; Sept 8; Sept 22, 1964
- 6-8 Caldara, W. Stuart. Mar 27, 1961 Caldwell, Edward F. and Co., Mar 27, 1941
- Dickerson, W.M. Jan 23, 1961, Jan 22, 1962
- Eames, Richard C., Sept 10, 1964
- Gibbons, George B, Jr. Jan 5, 1961, Mar 15, 1961
- Hinman, George R., Nov. 23, 1960; Nov 30, 1960; Dec. 15, 1960; June 4, 1962; Dec. 14, 196
- Jeffries, J. Amory., Nov. 25, 1959; Dec. 2, 1959; July 10, 1961; May 9, 1962; Setp. 25, 1962; Oct. 5, 1962; Dec. 5, 1962; April 25, 1963; May 1, 1963; May 31, 1963; Dec. 20, 1963; n.d.
- Knauth, Percy., Feb. 7, 1957; Jan. 21, 1957; Nov. 19, 1956
- 6-9 Morgan, Harry., April, 18, 1961 Mosbacher, Emil, Jr. (Bus) June 20, 1967
- Pratt, H. Irving., Jan 6, 1961; Jan 18, 1961; Jan 24; Apr 11, 1961; Apr 27, 1962; May 3; May 22; June 15, with letter from Wayne Sanborne, 1962
- Rimington, Critchell., Apr 1, 1964; Apr 10, 1964; Apr 22; May 28; June 11; June 25 Aug 3; Setp 10; Sept 16; Oct. 9, 1964
- 6-10 Robson, Vera. Mar 29, 1961 Roosevelt, George. May 1, 1961 Roosevelt, Julian K., Jan 10, 1961
- Sanborn, Wayne A., June 24, 1964 Scribner, Charles, Jr. June 1, 1964 Silk, George. June 13, 1967 Stephens, Olin J. Oct. 26, 1956
- Stephens, Roderick, Jr., Mar 29, 1941; Apr 3, 1941 Stewart, Wall. Nov. 17; Nov. 27; Dec. 7, 1959; Jan 5, 1960 Sunceville, Hugh. Feb. 28, 1963
- Valenzuela, Mario., Sept. 8, 1967; July 1967
- Ware, J. Herbert., April 9, 1960; Dec. 26, 1961
- Yachting Correspondence - Outgoing
- Sparkman & Stephens 1956: Nov. 10, Percy Knauth; Nov. 21, Knauth, 7-1 1941: March 26
- F. Gregg Bemis; Sept 28, Bemis; Oct. 8, Alexander P. Guest, etc. Oct. 9, Bemis; Oct 15, Guest, etc; Oct 19, Guest, etc; Oct 28, Bob; Nov. 20, W.A.W. Stewart; Nov. 27, Robert N. Bavier; Nov 30, Stewart; Amory Jeffries; Dec. 10, Jeffries, 1959: Sept. 25
- Bemis; Feb. 26, Mar 26, Apr 1, Apr 9, Apr 19, Bemis; Apr 20, Herbert Ware; Apr 21, May 2, May 10, May 31, June 1, June 2, Bemis; June 6, Racing Rules Committee; June 13, Bemis; June 22, Bemis; June 22, Racing Rules Committee; June 25, R.R.C.; June 28, Bemis; June 30, Bemis, 7-2 1960: Feb 5
- Gregg Bemis; Aug 10, Olin J. Stephens; Sept 30, Rules Racing Committee; Oct 4, Oct, 13, Oct 14, Bemis; Nov. 8, BaVier; Nov 16, Jeffries; Nov 28, Hinman; Dec 8, Hinman; Dec 29, Julian K. Roosevelt; Dec. 30, George B. Gibbons; Dec. 30, Bemis., 7-3 1960: July 1, July 6, July 13, July 21, July 25, Aug. 4
- Bemis; Irving Pratt; Jan 20, Pratt; Mar 31, Stuart Caldara; Apr 10, John S. Dickerson; Apr 21, Bemis; Apr 27, Committee on Racing Appeals; Jylian K. Roosevels; George B. Gibbons; W. Stuart Caldara; George F.B. Johnson; Committee on Racing Appeals; May 16, Bemis; June 21, Bemis; June 26, Bemis, June 30. Bemis; July 18, Jeffries; July 20, Bemis; July 27, Bemis; 1961: July 28, Bemis; Aug 1, Bemis; Aug 3, Bemis; Aug. 17, Oct 13, Oct 20, Oct 24,Bemis Nov 14, Jeffries; Nov. 27, Bemis; Nov. 28, Dec 4, Dec 13, Bemis, 7-4 1961: Jan 9
- Bemis; Jan 8, Jan 11, Apr 30, Pratt; May 3, Bemis; May 11, Pratt; May 18, Bemis; May 22, Jeffries; May 29, Bemis; July 19, Bemis; July 23, Bemis; Oct 2, Jeffries; Nov. 21, Jeffries; Nov. 23, Bavier, etc.; Nov. 28, Bemis; Dec. 10, Bemis; Jeffries; Dec. 12, Bemis; Dec. 19, Hinman; Dec. 28, Bemis, 7-5 1962: Jan 2
- Bemis; Feb. 27, Bemis; Mar 5, Hugh Sunceville; Mar 11, Bemis; Apr 24, Bemis; May 8, Bemis, etc; May 28, Jeffries; May 31, Bemis,etc.; June 3, Jeffries; July 8, Bemis; Oct. 16, Bemis; Oct. 16, Jeffries; Dec 30, Jeffries, 1-6 1963: Feb 26
- Critchell Rimington; Apr 13, Bemis; Apr 24, Bemis; Apr 28, Rimington; May 6, Bemis; May 8, Rimington; May 12, Rimington; May 26, Rimington; May 27, Bemis; May 29, Scribner; June 3, Rimington; June 19, Irving Pratt; June 19, Wayne A. Snaborn; July 22, Bemis; Sept. 14, Rimington; Sept 17, Richard C. Eames; Oct. 14, Rimington, 7-7 1964: Apr 7
- Mario Valenzuela; June 16, George Silk, 1967: July 18
- "TOO-RA-LOO-RA-LOO-RAL—That's An Irish Lullaby Words & Music by J. R. Shannon Copyright MCMXLIV by M. Witmark & Sons
- "Don't Fence Me In" lyric & music by Cole Porter Copyright MCMXLIV by HARMS Inc., N.Y.
- "Can't We Talk It Over" .MISSING,pp. 3-4 Lyric by Ned Washington; Music by Victor Young Copyright ? by Remick Music Corp.
- "There I Go Dreaming Again" Words & Music by Lew Brown and Ray Henderson Copyright 1932 by De Sylva, Brown and Henderson Inc.
- "I'm With You!" By Walter Donaldson Copyright 1931 by Donaldson, Douglas & Gumble Inc.
- "Were You Sincere?" Lyric by Jack Meskill; Music by Vincent Rose Copyright 19 31 by Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer Copr. New York, N.Y.
- "Isn't It Heavenly" Words by E. Y. Harburg; Music by Joseph Meyer Copyright MCMXXXIII by HARMS Incorporated
- "Adiqs" Lyric by Eddie Woods; Music and Spanish Translation by Enric Madriguera Copyright 1931 by Southern Music Publishing Co., Inc.
- "I Never Saw A Better Night" Lyrics by Johnny Mercer; Music by Lewis E. Gensler Copyright 1935 by Irving Berlin Inc.
- "Everything I Have Is Yours" Lyric by Harold Adamson; Melody by Burton Lane Copyright 1933 by Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer Corp., New York, N.Y.
- "Soft Lights And Sweet Music" MISSING| pp. 3-4 - By Irving Berlin Copyright 1932 by Irving Berlin Inc.
- "Dancing With My Shadow" Words & Music by Harry Woods Copyright 1934 by Campbell-Connelly & Co. Ltd. London England
- "About A Quarter To Nine" Lyric by A1 Dubin; Music by Harry Warren Copyright MCMXXXV by M. Witmark & Sons N.Y.
- "What's Keeping My Prince Charming?" Words by Mann Holiner; Music by Alberta Hichols Copyright MCMXXXI by Shapiro, Bernstein & Co. Inc. Cor.
- "Hello, Young Lovers" Words by Oscar Hammerstein 2nd; Music by Richard Rodgers Copyright 1951 by Richard Rodgers and Oscar Hammerstein 2nd Bonsoir (Good Night, Ch£ri) English Lyric by David Sidney; Music by Charles Maduro Copyright 1930 by Master Music, Inc.
- "Ain't Misbehavin'" Lyric by Andy Razaf; Music by Thomas Waller and Harry Brooks Copyright 1929 by Mills Music, Inc.
- "Strange Faces" By Nick Kenny, Al Vann, Teddy Powell Copyright 1935 by Superior Music Inc.
- "Evelina Words" by E. Y. Harburg; Music by Harold Arlen Copyright 194 4 by Crawford Music Corporation, N.Y.C.
- "You Can Make My Life A Bed Of Roses Words" Music by Lew Brown and Ray Henderson Copyright 1932 by De Sylva, Brown and Henderson Inc.
- "Tonight We Love Lyric" by Bobby Worth; Adaopted by Ray Austin & Freddy Martin Copyright 1941 by Maestro Music Co.
- "I Get A Kick Out Of You" Words and Music by Cole Porter Copyright MCMXXXIV by Harms Inc., N.Y.C.
- "There Goes That Song Again" Words by Sammy Carn; Music by Jule Styne Copyright MCMXLIV by Skidmore Music Co. Inc.
- "Whispering" Words & Music by John Schonberger, Richard Coburn, Vincent Rose Copyright 1920 Miller Music Corporation
- "South Of The Border" By Jimmy Kennedy and Michael Carr Copyright MCMXXXIX by The Peter Maurice Music Co. Ltd. London, England
- My Moonlight Madonna Lyric by Paul Francis Webster; Music by Zdenko Fibich Copyright MCMXXXIII by Carl Fischer Inc., New York
- "Only Another Boy And Girl" Words & Music by Cole Porter Copyright MCMXLIV by Chappell & Co. Inc., N.Y.C.
- "Sweet Madness" Words by Ned Washington; Music by Victor Young Copyright MCMXXXIII by HARMS Incorporated
- "The Trolley Song" Words & Music by Hugh Martin, Ralph Blane Copyright 1944 Leo Feist, Inc.
- "Stay As Sweet As You Are Lyric" Music by Mack Gordon and Harry Revel Copyright 1934 by Paramount Productions Music Corp.
- "Farming" Words & Music by Cole Porter Copyright MCMXLI by Chappell & Co., Inc., N.Y.C.
- "Too Many Tears" Words by Al Dubin; Music by Harry Warren Copyright MCMXXXII by M. Witmark & Sons, N.Y.
- "All Through The Night" Words & Music by Cole Porter Copyright MCMXXXIV by HARMS Inc., N.Y.C.
- "Falling In Love" Lyric by Earle Crooker; Music by Henry Sullivan Copyright 1931 by Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer Corp. New York, N.Y.
- "Love Never Went To College" Words by Lorenz Hart; Music by Richard Rodgers Copyright MCMXXXIX by Chappell & Co. Inc., N.Y.C.
- "I'll Follow My Secret Heart" Words & Music by Noel Coward Copyright MCMXXXIV by Chappell & Co., Ltd.
- "I'll Follow My Secret Heart" Same as above, MISSING pp. 1,2, & 7 (front & back covers)
- "All Of Me" INCOMPLETE (pp. 3-4 only) By Seymour_Simons & Gerald Marks Copyright 1931 by Irving Berlin
- Register
- CHILDHOOD: (Box 1., Folder 1.)
  - 6 mos., in carriage (Box 1., Folder 1.)
  - 1 yr., seated in studio (2 photos, 1 in color), W. Kurtz, N.Y.C. (Box 1., Folder 1.)
  - Studio, wearing fur-trimmed hat and coat (2 photos, 1 copy), W. Kurtz, N.Y.C. (Box 1., Folder 1.)
  - Seated with young girl (HSV?) (Box 1., Folder 1.)
  - 1-1% yrs. old, seated on cushion in chair, wearing dress, W. Kurtz, N.Y.C. (Box 1., Folder 1.)
  - 2-3 yrs. old, headshot, Navarz, Paris (Box 1., Folder 1.)
  - Portrait, framed, with kittens and basket of flowers, Paris, by C. Chaplin, 1887. 3-4 yrs. old, wearing kilt, L. Joliot, Paris (Box 1., Folder 1.)
  - 3-4 yrs. old, wearing navy suit, in mountains, L. Joliot, Paris (Box 1., Folder 1.)
  - 3-4 yrs. old, wearing sailor suit, seated on steps, Ludovici's Portraits, N.Y.C. (Box 1., Folder 1.)
  - 4-5 yrs. old, mounted snapshot, wearing sailor hat and coat, in yard, with dog, doghouse (Box 1., Folder 1.)
  - 4-5 yrs. old, head profile, wearing sailor suit, W. Kurtz, N.Y.C. (Box 1., Folder 1.)
  - 4-5 yrs. old, wearing knicker suit, standing, M. Raynaud, Nice (Box 1., Folder 1.)
  - 7-8 yrs. old, mounted snapshot, in front of gate (Box 1., Folder 1.)
  - 8-9 yrs. old, mounted snapshot, in front of porch (Box 1., Folder 1.)
  - 11-12 yrs. old, portrait, with dog, Tvanovitch, Paris (Box 1., Folder 1.)
  - 12-13 yrs. old, portrait, standing (Box 1., Folder 1.)
  - Dog (3 photos) (Box 1., Folder 1.)
  - YOUNG MAN: (Box 1., Folder 2.)
  - Seated in chair, wearing suit, Alman & Co., N.Y. (Box 1., Folder 2.)
- St. Mark's School, Class of 1903, graduation day (Copy) (HSV-top left) (Box 1., Folder 2.)
  - Navy Reserve groups on board (2 photos) (Box 1., Folder 2.)
- MIDDLE YEARS: (Box 1., Folder 3.)
  - Seated in cane chair, wearing sport coat, outside (Box 1., Folder 3.)
  - On board, wearing Navy hat (Box 1., Folder 3.)
  - By plane, with pipe (Box 1., Folder 3.)
  - By plane, wearing overcoat and hat (Box 1., Folder 3.)
  - On terrace with man in tails, champagne, N.Y. (Box 1., Folder 3.)
  - Near tennis courts with racket and balls, wearing sweater, N.Y. (Box 1., Folder 3.)
  - On board, yacht, Vagrant, N.Y. (Box 1., Folder 3.)
  - On board, with Mrs. Vanderbilt and two men, N.Y., 1939 (Rosenfeld) (Box 1., Folder 3.)
  - HSV, on board, with woman and man, Times-Picayune, New Orleans (Box 1., Folder 3.)
  - On board, with four men (Box 1., Folder 3.)
  - In bed, Mr. and Mrs. Vanderbilt (Box 1., Folder 3.)
  - Carter Hall, Millwood, VA., HSV and Mrs., dog and five others on columned porch, June 1941 (Box 1., Folder 3.)
- LATER YEARS: (Box 1., Folder 4.)
  - On board, with two others (Box 1., Folder 4.)
  - On board, interior, 1967?, Newport Daily News (Box 1., Folder 4.)
  - Beside mantle with trophies (home), 1967? (Box 1., Folder 4.)
  - Going on board, cart, Mrs. V. and six others (Box 1., Folder 4.)
  - Presenting trophies (Box 1., Folder 4.)
  - At table, with cards, bridgehand (3 views) (Box 1., Folder 4.)
  - Seated in home (2 photos) (Box 1., Folder 4.)
  - In cap and gown, Frissell (Box 1., Folder 4.)
- OVERSIZE: (Box 1., Folder 5.)
  - 8 x 10" of painted portrait at helm (2 photos, middle yrs.) (Box 1., Folder 5.)
  - Playing bridge, Frissell (1 with 3 others, 1 alone, late middle yrs.) (Box 1., Folder 5.)
  - Photo portrait, Kazanjian (middle yrs.) (Box 1., Folder 5.)
  - 11 x 14 proofs, portraits, at home, in study (7 photos, late middle yrs.) (Box 1., Folder 5.)
  - 11 x 14 proofs, Blackstone-Shelburne, N.Y. (2 photos) (Box 1., Folder 5.)
  - 11x14, head, Wielar, N.Y. (late middle yrs.) (Box 1., Folder 5.)
  - Seated in chair, Frissell (late middle yrs.) (Box 1., Folder 5.)
  - Seated in study, Frissell (2 photos, late middle yrs.) (Box 1., Folder 5.)
  - At bridge, Frissell (2 photos) (Box 1., Folder 5.)
  - On farm, pitching hay (2) (Box 1., Folder 5.)
  - On farm, with corn (Box 1., Folder 5.)
  - On farm, on tractor (Box 1., Folder 5.)
  - On farm, discussing plans with Mrs. V (2) (Box 1., Folder 5.)
  - On farm, in cornfield (2) (Box 1., Folder 5.)
  - With Gertrude and dog (Box 1., Folder 5.)
- FAMILY (Box 1., Folder 6.)
  - Commodore Cornelius Vanderbilt (Box 1., Folder 6.)
  - William Henry Vanderbilt (Box 1., Folder 6.)
  - William Kissam Vanderbilt (Box 1., Folder 6.)
  - Consuelo Vanderbilt (Box 1., Folder 6.)
  - Woman, seated in chair (Box 1., Folder 6.)
  - Three girls, playing guitar, Jennie Liffany, Evie Wollins Folder 7-SNAPSHOTS, NEGATIVES: (Box 1., Folder 6.)
- SNAPSHOTS, NEGATIVES: (Box 1., Folder 7.)
  - Plane (Box 1., Folder 7.)
  - Head (middle yrs.) (Box 1., Folder 7.)
  - Travel (Box 1., Folder 7.)
  - Farm (Box 1., Folder 7.)
  - Horseback (Box 1., Folder 7.)
  - Party (Box 1., Folder 7.)
  - Pool (Box 1., Folder 7.)
- Family and Friends (Box 2., Folder 1.)
  - Man holding Army-Navy trophy (Box 2., Folder 1.)
  - Muriel, inscribed to Gertie and Uncle Harold, Feb. 1970 (Box 2., Folder 1.)
  - Boy, aged 3-4 yrs., in church pew (Box 2., Folder 1.)
  - Duchess of Marlboro, Rosieta with son, Edward (Box 2., Folder 1.)
  - Young man, in doorway, with champagne (Box 2., Folder 1.)
  - Woman, with son and daughter, 1960's (Box 2., Folder 1.)
  - Portrait of woman, 1920's (Box 2., Folder 1.)
  - Man, in shirt sleeves (Box 2., Folder 1.)
  - Child, aged 5-6 yrs. (Box 2., Folder 1.)
  - Man, in uniform (Box 2., Folder 1.)
  - Man, in Navy uniform (Box 2., Folder 1.)
  - Family portrait, in front of portrait of Commodore (Box 2., Folder 1.)
  - Man, standing, with hands in pockets, Christmas 1939 (Box 2., Folder 1.)
  - Man, rowing boat (Box 2., Folder 1.)
  - Duke and Duchess of Windsor (signed) with two men, standing in front of plane, April 23, 1941 (Box 2., Folder 1.)
- HSV, MISCELLANEOUS (Box 2., Folder 2.)
- HSV, UNIDENTIFIED: (Box 2., Folder 3.)
  - Portraits (Box 2., Folder 3.)
  - Group photos (Box 2., Folder 3.)
- BOATING (Box 2., Folder 4.)
- RESIDENCES (Box 2., Folder 5.)
- DOGS (Box 2., Folder 6.)
- TRIPS (Box 2., Folder 7.)
  - including pages from scrapbook (Box 2., Folder 7.)
- PLANES, BOATS (Box 2., Folder 8.)
- VANDERBILT UNIVERSITY, HARVARD: (Box 2., Folder 9.)
  - HSV with Eldon Stevenson (Box 2., Folder 9.)
  - HSV with Flemings, Mrs. V (Box 2., Folder 9.)
  - HSV with Branscombs, Purdys, Mrs. V (Box 2., Folder 9.)
  - HSV with Branscombs, Purdys, unidentified (Box 2., Folder 9.)
  - 1960's Board of Trust, Rand (Box 2., Folder 9.)
  - 1951 Board of Trust, steps of Kirkland (Box 2., Folder 9.)
  - View of campus, student dormitories, quadrangle, seen from above (Box 2., Folder 9.)
  - HSV statue, unfinished (2) (Box 2., Folder 9.)
  - HSV statue, on campus (Box 2., Folder 9.)
  - HSV memorial service, crowd (Box 2., Folder 9.)
  - HSV with Alexander Heard, at Heard installation as Chancellor (Box 2., Folder 9.)
  - William H. Vanderbilt, wreath-laying ceremony, great-great grandson of Commodore (4 photos) (Box 2., Folder 9.)
  - Kennedy visit (Box 2., Folder 9.)